<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Solar Grammars</title>
		<description></description>
		<link></link>
		<atom:link href="/rss-feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Palettes and  graphs as color context</title>
				
					<dc:creator>Solar Grammars</dc:creator>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Colors are usually perceived in as part of a composition. It is rare that we can 
find them in isolation in nature. In that sense,  probably what colors evoke is 
tightly associated to the perception of a colorful &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;context&lt;/code&gt;. In other words, how we perceive 
a certain type of red, does not depend only on such color, but also on the colors
that surround it.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/blog/colors-in-context.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/colors-in-context.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Grounding Color Comparatives</title>
				
					<dc:creator>Solar Grammars</dc:creator>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;The methods  we have covered so far allowed  us to learn  a direct mapping between colors and language. One possible limitation of those approaches is that in reality color perception is intrinsically contextual, in the sense that usually we come up with a description for a newly seen color based on a predefined reference. For example, when
we say a given color is &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mustard yellow&lt;/code&gt;, we are basically relating our experienced notion of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mustard&lt;/code&gt;  and a reference &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;yellow&lt;/code&gt; and associating them
to express our perception through language. Another example can be seen when we say &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;dark green&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;deep blue&lt;/code&gt;. In these cases we are adding an adjective to a color based or our predefined notion of it. In that sense, in order to communicate our perception of  &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;dark green&lt;/code&gt;, we use our preconceived reference of what we understand as &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;green&lt;/code&gt; and its &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;dark&lt;/code&gt; variant. In this process, we are implicitly internalizing that the color we are perceiving is &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;darker&lt;/code&gt; than 
the reference we have.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/blog/grounding-color-comparatives.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/grounding-color-comparatives.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Learning Color-Language Representations</title>
				
					<dc:creator>Solar Grammars</dc:creator>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Grounded language learning tasks allow to characterize the relationships between words semantically (abstracting from their symbolic nature), and based 
on that, contribute to understanding the principles of language 
acquisition. In that sense, color description, or more generally,  the generation of color language, is a relevant aspect for  understanding the emergence of human expression.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/blog/learning-color-language-representations.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/learning-color-language-representations.html</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
