<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Solar Grammars</title>
		<description></description>
		<link></link>
		<atom:link href="/rss-feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Autoencoding Color-Language Representations</title>
				
					<dc:creator>Solar Grammars</dc:creator>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Autoencoding color representations&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 01:15:37 +0900</pubDate>
				<link>http://pablomentat.duckdns.org:4000/blog/aecolors.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pablomentat.duckdns.org:4000/blog/aecolors.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Macropad Building Instructions</title>
				
					<dc:creator>Solar Grammars</dc:creator>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;SU120 appears to be an extremely flexible PCB for unleashing our 
creativity in terms of mechanical keyboard crafting. Here I will 
quickly summarize the steps I followed to build a very basic
macropad, just scratching the surface of what seems to be possible.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 01:03:54 +0900</pubDate>
				<link>http://pablomentat.duckdns.org:4000/notes/macropad.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pablomentat.duckdns.org:4000/notes/macropad.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Program Repair by Policy Learning (in progress)</title>
				
					<dc:creator>Solar Grammars</dc:creator>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Repairing a bug is essentially a search problem. At source code level, it is necessary to find the combination of structural and syntactic changes that lead us obtain a version of the code on which the reported fault is not present anymore. Therefore, the code needs to be transformed, from a defective state to a healthy one. We assume this transformation can be achieved by adding, modifying or even deleting certain portions of the code. Most existing techniques for repair take the problem only from the source code perspective, and therefore, only consider the syntactic aspects of the program. While this configuration appear as the most natural approach, I think we can explore a more top-down way, in the sense of explicitly consider how humans find their way to fix a bug.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
				<link>http://pablomentat.duckdns.org:4000/blog/hoc-program-repair.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pablomentat.duckdns.org:4000/blog/hoc-program-repair.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Combining Word and Character level Representations from Color Descriptions</title>
				
					<dc:creator>Solar Grammars</dc:creator>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;We have been exploring the relationship between language and colors
from both word and character level perspectives, but in 
isolation. Then, the natural question that arises is what 
if subword structures play an important role in color 
grounding?  In other words, what if we combine character
and word level representations when modeling color-language
relationships?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
				<link>http://pablomentat.duckdns.org:4000/blog/color-gates.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pablomentat.duckdns.org:4000/blog/color-gates.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Palettes and Graphs as Color Context</title>
				
					<dc:creator>Solar Grammars</dc:creator>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Colors are usually perceived as part of a composition. It is rare that we can 
find them in isolation in nature. Sometimes we find
articles, usually associated to marketing, where people make a direct relationship
between a color and an emotion or a feeling. For example, when the color
red is associated to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;passion&lt;/code&gt; and green to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;hope&lt;/code&gt;. Such relationships could
be true to some extent, but I think it is also important to consider the context associated
to such perceptions. A red color indeed can express passion, but in some cases, given 
the set of other colors present in the composition, it could also express sadness or fear.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
				<link>http://pablomentat.duckdns.org:4000/blog/colors-in-context.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pablomentat.duckdns.org:4000/blog/colors-in-context.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Grounding Color Comparatives</title>
				
					<dc:creator>Solar Grammars</dc:creator>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;The methods  we have covered so far allowed  us to learn  a direct mapping between colors and language. One possible limitation of those approaches is that in reality color perception is intrinsically contextual, in the sense that usually we come up with a description for a newly seen color based on a predefined reference. For example, when
we say a given color is &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mustard yellow&lt;/code&gt;, we are basically relating our experienced notion of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mustard&lt;/code&gt;  and a reference &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;yellow&lt;/code&gt; and associating them
to express our perception through language. Another example can be seen when we say &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;dark green&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;deep blue&lt;/code&gt;. In these cases we are adding an adjective to a color based or our predefined notion of it. In that sense, in order to communicate our perception of  &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;dark green&lt;/code&gt;, we use our preconceived reference of what we understand as &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;green&lt;/code&gt; and its &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;dark&lt;/code&gt; variant. In this process, we are implicitly internalizing that the color we are perceiving is &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;darker&lt;/code&gt; than 
the reference we have.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
				<link>http://pablomentat.duckdns.org:4000/blog/grounding-color-comparatives.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pablomentat.duckdns.org:4000/blog/grounding-color-comparatives.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Learning Color-Language Representations</title>
				
					<dc:creator>Solar Grammars</dc:creator>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Grounded language learning tasks allow to characterize the relationships between words semantically (abstracting from their symbolic nature), and based 
on that, contribute to understanding the principles of language 
acquisition. In that sense, color description, or more generally,  the generation of color language, is a relevant aspect for  understanding the emergence of human expression.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
				<link>http://pablomentat.duckdns.org:4000/blog/learning-color-language-representations.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pablomentat.duckdns.org:4000/blog/learning-color-language-representations.html</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
